# Yegor Dumnov

### Senior Software Developer

+7 904 034 40 82 | yegor@dumnov.com | linkedin.com/in/edumnov

#### Summary

Creative and passionate Backend Engineer with 8+ years experience in developing, maintaining and supporting regular and high-loaded software using a modern stack of technologies, following Design Patterns, DRY, KISS, SOLID, Clean Code principles and DevOps culture. Articulate communicator and remote worker.

## Experience

# **Cloud Developer**

Windisch, Switzerland (Remote) (Full-Time Contract)

SAP

Oct. 2018 - Present

- Developed several microservices using Spring Boot and Java on different business domains
- Made an API with highest load ratio 15 times faster by SQL optimizations
- Created a coding productivity workshop for more than 100 developers
- Participated in rotating on-call duties, including incident management
- Contributed to the platform which allowed to apply Event-Driven-Design
- Upgrade the services from Java 8 to Java 11
- Leaded the memory tuning of Java-based Apps
- Improved Integration tests approach, which allowed increase case coverage, prevent problems and considerably reduced test flakiness

## Software Engineer

Chicago, IL (Remote), (Part-Time Contract)

Chicago Deal Vault

Jun~2017-Feb~2018

- Familiarized myself with a new subject real estate, within a short time
- Implemented a mortgage calculator
- Implemented a direct mail distribution subsystem
- Implemented a generator of analytical reports

# Lead Java Developer

Moscow, Russia

BSC

Apr 2014 - Oct 2018

- Took the lead of a small team of developers on a server for Mobile Bank App Server for Top-3 Russian Bank
- Took the lead of a small team of developers on a server for Stock Analytics Apps Server for Top-10 Russian Broker
- Switched a huge legacy project from SVN to Git, which allowed to establish a proper code reviews and run more agile release process
- Developed a customer support chat on bank web application for Top-3 Russian Bank
- Made several prototypes of Internet Banks within a short time which helped the organization to win contracts
- Mentored a group of Junior Developers
- Contacted directly with customers about technical details and issues
- Made a backend of a dashboard app for Top-5 Russian Broker

## Junior Developer

FGI ARRIAH

Vladimir, Russia

Jun 2012 - Apr 2014

• Significantly improved the functionality of the Federal Service for Veterinary and Phytosanitary Surveillance official website, thus, the information on global trade and episootic situation became more structured and detailed

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Kotlin, GO, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks: Spring(Boot, Cloud, Web, Security, DM etc..), Hibernate, JSF, Liferay

Version Control: Git, Mercurial

CI/CD: Jenkins, Bamboo, GitHub Actions, Mesos, Marathon, Ansible, Docker Special Technologies: Kafka, ElasticSearch, Hystrix, Hazelcast, Redis, Mockito

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Industry Standards: Microservices, REST API, RPC, SOAP, Event-Driven Architecture, Domain-Driven Design,

Test-Driven Development

#### **EDUCATION**

## Vladimir State University

Vladimir, Russia